HANDI SULYANSAH

Poris Indah Blok C 502, 14158, Tangerang, Indonesia | 0812-9166-2594 | handi.sulyansah@gmail.com | https://ndiyansah.github.io/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/handisulyansah/

SUMMARY

Being a Front end Developer in PT Generasi Digital Internasional (GDILab.com), we're building a Social Intelligence Platform to connect Micro Business Players and Influencers. In addition, having total experiences for at least less than 1 years as Front end Developer has enhanced HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP and modern Front end Development, I am truly passionate about have a clear logical mind with a practical approach to problem solving and a drive to see things through to completion, I enjoy working on my own initiative or in a team in short, I am reliable, trustworthy, hardworking and eager to learn and have genuine interest in company.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Engineering, July 2016 Faculty Of Computer Science – Bina Nusantara University

Minor in Database System

Build an internal application for Bogor Public Hospital

The purpose of the research conducted in (RSUD) General Hospital Bogor City is designing application database systems outpatient for recording and storage of data in the field of hospital outpatient, which includes registration outpatient clinics, laboratories, fields of physiotherapy, radiology, pharmacy and payment. The method used in this thesis is the design of (DBLC) Database System Development lifecycle consisting of conceptual database design, database design logical and physical database design.

Technologies: PHP,HTML5,CSS3,JQuery,AJAX and MySQL.

Build an Blue Jack Project application for Visual Programming Project using VB.NET and LINQ for Database System.

Courses included:

Basic Programming LINUX distro FEDORA12, January 2011 – December 2011

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front end Developer, March 2017- Present

Pt Generasi Digital Internasional (GDILab.com), Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

- Rebuild product dashboard micro report
- Build new product Social Mater
- Rebuild product Report Automation
 Responsible for the translation of UI/UX design wireframes to actual code, maintaining
 styleguides, code conventions, creating UI components, and improving web performance
 from front end side. This process is also supported by back-end developers, who are
 responsible for server-side application logic and integration of the work.

Software Engineering Internship, April 2015- July 2015 Microsoft Indonesia, Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

- Team member of MACH (Microsoft academy collage hire)
- Analytic millions record data
- Data Mining

Web Programmer Internship, January 2015- March 2016

Ministry of Industry Indonesia, Greater Jakarta Area , Indonesia

- Team member of the Binus Student Internship, 3 member for this Group
- As Front-End Engineer For Biro Perencanaan (Project Name), internal system that limits access by the system only in that section
- Build GUI Tools For Biro Perencanaan.
- Developed prototype of new product enhancement for Biro Perencanaan, Programs were written in JavaScript, MySql, PHP,CSS and HTML5.

.....

Organization Experience

Creative Division , May 2015 – Present Youth Corps Indonesia, Greater Jakarta Area , Indonesia

Youth Corps Indonesia is an NGO that focuses on youth empowerment for the development of Indonesia. We provide access to information, capacity building and youth collaborate to produce youth-based solutions for human development better.

Coordinator of research and development, September 2012 – July 2013 HIMTI (Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Informatika), Greater Jakarta Area , Indonesia

The idea was to establish a platform for the students Department of Information Engineering thus proved to be real in the development of IT in Indonesia as well as train management capabilities of leadership in the organization.

ACTIVITIES AND VOLUNTEERS

- Developer, Youth Corps Indonesia, 2015-Present
- Team Leader Tenant, Bravo! Event, 2015-2016
- Coordinator Education, Event Google Education in Summit Indonesia 2015, Google Indonesia, November 2015
- Coordinator Hacktoon, Event Google Hacktoon in Indonesia 2015, Google Indonesia, December 2015
- Team Leader Finish Line and Packaging, Event Jakarta Marathon, Insipiro Group, September 2015
- Member Google Workshop Volunteer, Kibar (Google Group), January 2015 July 2015
- Digital Corner, Event HaiDay 2015, National Geographic Indonesia, July 2015
- Coordinator, Event Jakarta Marathon, Insipiro Group, September 2014
- Coordinator of research and development, HIMTI Binus University, 2012-2013

SKILLS

Hard Skill

• Programming : HTML

CSS

Javascript

JSP

PHP

• FrameWork : Twitter Bootstrap

Semantic UI

React.js

• Library/APIs : JQuery

Node.Js AJAX

• Storage : MySQL

• Tools : Sublime Text

Notepad++

Atom

• Design Tools : Adobe illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Interest

Startup, Technology, Social, Reed Book, Traveler, Music, SDG's